CURTHBERT CHAWIRA

Computer Engineer



- HARARE, ZIMBABWE
- ✓ curthbertchawira2016@gmail.com
 - +263 78 500 14 94

Profile

A fully qualified Computer Engineer with experience as IT Support for network, operating systems and applications at the end user level. I am enthusiastic about developing a career in computer Engineering. My ability to stay focussed under pressure allows me to perform efficiently and with precision in high demand situations. I possess excellent analytical and problem-solving skills with the ability to make independent judgements. I strive to be empathetic, respectful and cooperative in all interactions. I am highly numerate and with a solid mathematical scientific background. With a strong commitment to my personal development and achievement, I endeavour to be resourceful and creative in all my endeavours, bringing a fresh perspective to situations while upholding core company values.

Projects

Churn predictor,, Predict if customer is going churn or not. I used Python as programming language and also technologies such as Machine Learning 09/2018 – 12/2018

Professional Experience

Software Developer (Intern),

European University of Lefke 06/2019 – 08/2019 | Lefke, Cyprus

As part of my prerequisite at my university I am allocated 45 days to do my internship training. I did my internship at the Robotics Lab at Near East University. I worked with Arduino on different projects, I also worked with Raspberry pi. I also combined Raspberry Pi and Arduino on some projects

Web Developer, Gigabyte Ltd 06/2019 - 09/2019 | Nicosia, Cyprus Worked as part of a development team to implement the use of Flutter and Dart. Collaborated with the supervisor to successfully debug issues in the GUI for the mobile application. Participated in clientbased projects to design and implement mobile applications using dart and flutter. Collaborated in and participated in designing a UI and implementing the database by migrating a web-based barcode system into a mobile application. Worked as part of a team tasked to design, develop and implement an application for small businesses. Developed project spec questionnaire to identify client needs and streamline the project development process by writing the software requirements and the project documentation

Information Systems Technical / Software Development, *Pnrhost*

01/2021 – 04/2021 | Harare, Zimbabwe Software Development. Website using WordPress. Analyse and resolves service desk support problems. Provide end user training and support. Provides with IT systems support and maintenance on desktops, laptops, server hardware, work. Infrastructure, Communication systems and carryout end user support. Backup of active equipment configurations and configuration of the backup equipment.

Car rental management, Web-based online application for managing car for rental. I used html, CSS, JavaScript as frontend designing, PHP and SQL for backend 02/2017 – 06/2017

Skills

Troubleshooting applications, hardware and software, Network security, Dynamic Web design and Developer, Front end and Backend developer, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, ASP.Net and PHP, SQL, NoSQL, MySQL, and Oracle SQL developer, Software programmer (C++, C, Basic, C#, Linux, Python etc.) Windows Server, Information security. Database Management Systems (SQL, MySQL, Oracle, and XML) Database Security Cisco networking (CCNA routing and switching, security) Software installations on desktop and laptops, Databackup

Software Developer, *Dekaben Bilisim* 06/2021 – 11/2021 | Girne, Cyprus

- Participating in daily scrum meetings, sprint planning, unit testing and bug fixes.
- Developing and designing pages and forms using PHP, MySQL, HTML, and CSS for a new marketplace.
- In charge of designing, developing and deploying a hybrid App for a marketplace with ionic react and node.js as the
- Experience with GitHub as the source control.
- Working with other developers and designers to develop the website and applications.
- Designing, development, deployment, and maintenance of all menu maintenance portal code using PHP, MySQL,
- HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

Frontend Developer, MBL Hightech 01/2022 – 08/2022 | Girne, Cyprus

- Participating in daily scrum meetings, sprint planning, unit testing and bug fixes.
- Agile/Scrum experience with React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, typeorm, and Webpack.
- Automation experience with Cypress, and Puppeteer.
- Testing API endpoints with swagger and postman.
- Integrating the frontend with the back-end.
- Experience with Bitbucket and Github
- Managing, maintaining and developing new features of a client-zone, developing features like the IB module.
- Working closely with clients, with improvements to their websites and integration.

Education

BSc in Computer Engineering, Bachelor of Computer Sciences in Computer

Engineering, *European University of Lefke* 2016 – 2022 | Lefke, Cyprus